A Guide to the Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts Overseer of the Poor Annual Reports and Checklists, 1800-1909
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts Overseer of the Poor Annual Reports and Checklists, 1800-1909
The Library of Virginia
APA 739
18.75 (36 boxes)
Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts (1776-1928)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
A number of items have been pulled for conservation and are identified by pull slips.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Auditor of Public Accounts.
Biographical Information
In 1780 the Virginia General Assembly replaced the Anglican vestries and churchwardens of the colonial period with elected bodies called Overseers of the Poor. The Overseers of the Poor made policy, levied taxes, distributed public money, and dealt with the underprivileged as they thought best. Some counties build poor houses while others did not. The Overseers provided food, clothing, shelter, and medical treatment for the persons who were too poor to support themselves or too ill to provide for their basic needs. The Overseers took over the supervision of the poorhouses and workhouses built by the vestries and built new poorhouses and workhouses where they were needed. On 20 February 1829 the General Assembly passed an act requiring that the local clerks or agents responsible for the records of the Overseers of the Poor, or the President of the County Board of the Overseers of the Poor, to report their proceedings annually to the auditor of public accounts. The reporting period was retroactive to 1 January 1800. On 14 March 1910 the General Assembly repealed the sections of the Code of Virginia that required that the reports be sent annually to the auditor of public accounts.
Scope and Content
The Overseer of the Poor Annual Reports and Checklists, 1800-1909, are housed in 36 boxes and are arranged alphabetically into two series. Series have been designated for Series I: Virginia Cities and Counties and Series II: West Virginia Cities and Counties. The Annual Reports and Checklists cover the years 1800-1864, 1871-1881, 1884-1907, and 1909.
The Reports and Checklists include written reports and statistics on the number of poor whites and free blacks maintiained at the public charge; the amount of poor rates levied annual for their support; the amount of donations for the use of the poor from individuals; number of poor maintained at poor or work house with the annual expence of their maintenance; and sometimes minutes are included from meetings. Beginning in the 1840s, more detailed information is included such as the names of the poor (white, free black, and slave), age, physical condition, and morals. Of note several counties were extra descriptive in their reports, such as Pittsylvania County in Virginia and Hardy County in West Virginia. Included are reports for most of the counties in Virginia, also including counties in West Virginia up to 1862.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in the following series:
Series I: Virginia Cities and Counties, 1800-1909
Series II: West Virginia Cities and Counties, 1800-1862
Contents List
- Series I: Virginia, 1800-1909., Extent: 30 boxes (15.75 cu. ft.). (Box 1-15; and 20-26; and 28-36)
  Arranged alphabetically by city or county name and then chronological. Oversize materials were separated and placed in oversize boxes though everything is listed in chronological order in the finding aid. Researchers should pay special attention to note the box numbers.
  - Accomack County, 1829-1847. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Accomack County, 1851-1865. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Accomack County [oversize], 1876-1877, 1879, 1881, 1909. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Albemarle County, 1800-1849. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Albemarle County [oversize], 1851-1856. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Albemarle County [oversize], 1860-1864, 1874, 1876, 1879-1880. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Alexandria, 1849. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alexandria [oversize], 1851-1852. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Alleghany County, 1824-1849. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alleghany County, 1851-1860. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alleghany County [oversize], 1875-1879. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Amelia County, 1800-1835, 1840-1845, 1851-1853, 1860, 1863. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Amherst County, 1829-1839, 1845-1849, 1851-1852. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Amherst County [oversize], 1860, 1863. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Appomattox County, 1851. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Appomattox County [oversize], 1875, 1877. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Augusta County, 1829, 1835-1836, 1840-1845. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Augusta County [oversize], 1852-1859. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Augusta County [oversize], 1860-1861, 1863-1864, 1874-1875, 1877, 1879. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Bath County, 1829-1851, 1875. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bath County [oversize], 1874, 1876, 1878. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Bedford County, 1829-1851, 1860. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bedford County [oversize], 1875-1876, 1879. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Bland County [oversize], 1863, 1875-1877, 1880. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Botetourt County, 1800-1851, 1856. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Botetourt County [oversize], 1861, 1875-1876, 1880-1881. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Brunswick County, 1800-1852, 1860. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Brunswick County [oversize], 1876-1881. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Buchanan County [oversize], 1860-1861, 1863, 1876, 1878. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Buckingham County, 1829-1851, 1863. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Buckingham County [oversize], 1860, 1875, 1879. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Campbell County, 1800-1852, 1859-1860. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Campbell County [oversize], 1862-1863. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Caroline County, 1800-1856, 1860. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Caroline County [oversize], 1894. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Carroll County, 1843-1859. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Carroll County [oversize], 1860-1861, 1863, 1879. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Charles City County, 1811-1850. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Charles City County [oversize], 1852-1861, 1877-1878. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Charlotte County, 1829-1849. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Charlotte County, 1851-1863. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Chesterfield County, 1800-1849. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Chesterfield County, 1851-1864. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Chesterfield County [oversize], 1878-1880. (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Clarke County, 1837-1852, 1876. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Clarke County [oversize], 1860. (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Craig County, 1851-1852, 1860. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Craig County [oversize], 1894, 1909. (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Culpeper County, 1800-1857, 1874-1875. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Culpeper County [oversize], 1876-1877, 1880-1881. (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Cumberland County, 1829-1849. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Cumberland County, 1851-1860. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Danville, 1859-1860. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Dinwiddie County, 1800-1846. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Dinwiddie County, 1851-1860. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Dinwiddie County [oversize], 1871, 1879-1880. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Elizabeth City County, 1820-1860. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Elizabeth City County [oversize], 1876-1877, 1880. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Essex County, 1800-1851. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Essex County [oversize], 1860, 1876-1879. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Fairfax County, 1800-1851. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Fairfax County [oversize], 1860, 1871, 1873, 1875-1877. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Fauquier County, 1829-1851. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Fauquier County [oversize], 1874. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Floyd County, 1832-1849. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Floyd County, 1850-1859. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Floyd County [oversize], 1860, 1863-1864, 1872-1880. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Fluvanna County, 1800-1860. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Fluvanna County [oversize], 1873-1876. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Franklin County, 1800-1855. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Franklin County [oversize], 1860-1861, 1871, 1873, 1875-1876. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Frederick County, 1800-1853. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Frederick County [oversize], 1871-1875, 1877, 1881, 1894. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Fredericksburg, 1830-1853. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fredericksburg [oversize], 1860. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Giles County, 1806-1849. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Giles County, 1850-1859. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Giles County [oversize], 1860-1861. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Gloucester County, 1800-1851. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Gloucester County [oversize], 1860. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Goochland County, 1800-1861, 1863. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Grayson County, 1800-1864. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Grayson County [oversize], 1860, 1876, 1878-1881. (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Greene County, 1838-1860. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Greensville County, 1800-1849. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Greensville County, 1850-1861. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Halifax County, 1800-1850, 1860. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Halifax County [oversize], 1851-1853, 1876, 1879. (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Hanover County, 1800-1849. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Hanover County, 1850-1860, 1864. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Henrico County, 1829-1850, 1855-1860. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Henrico County [oversize], 1851-1855, 1861-1864. (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Henrico County [oversize], 1875-1878, 1880. (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Henry County, 1800-1849. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Henry County, 1851-1860. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Henry County [oversize], 1861, 1875. (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Highland County, 1847-1857. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Highland County [oversize], 1876, 1881. (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Isle of Wight County, 1802-1849. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Isle of Wight County, 1850-1857, 1860. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Isle of Wight County [oversize], 1859, 1877, 1879, 1880. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - James City County, 1800-1860. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - King George County, 1800-1859. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - King George County [oversize], 1861, 1877, 1879-1880. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - King and Queen County, 1800-1849. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - King and Queen County, 1850-1857, 1874-1875. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - King and Queen County [oversize], 1859-1860, 1876-1878, 1880, 1894. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - King William County, 1815-1849. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - King William County, 1851-1864. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Lancaster County, 1816-1835. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Lancaster County [oversize], 1851-1861, 1877-1878, 1909. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Lee County, 1812-1847, 1860. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Lee County [oversize], 1880. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Loudoun County, 1800-1853. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Loudoun County [oversize], 1876-1877. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Louisa County, 1800-1849. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Louisa County, 1850-1860. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Louisa County [oversize], 1852, 1859, 1861, 1863. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Lunenburg County, 1812-1849. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Lunenburg County, 1851-1859. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Lunenburg County [oversize], 1861, 1863, 1876-1878, 1880-1881, 1909. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Lynchburg [oversize], 1800-1829. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Lynchburg City, 1830-1856. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Madison County, 1800-1851. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Madison County [oversize], 1860, 1876. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Mathews County, 1816-1857. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Mathews County [oversize], 1860, 1876. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Mecklenburg County [oversize], 1800-1829, 1852, 1853, 1876, 1879-1881, 1884. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Mecklenburg County, 1840-1851, 1854, 1862-1864. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Middlesex County, 1800-1852. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Middlesex County [oversize], 1860. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Montgomery County, 1810-1856, 1861. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Montgomery County [oversize], 1860, 1880. (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Nansemond County, 1818-1849. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Nansemond County, 1850-1860. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Nansemond County [oversize], 1876-1877, 1879-1881, 1909. (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Nelson County, 1807-1849. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Nelson County, 1850-1855. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Nelson County [oversize], 1860. (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - New Kent County, 1800-1841. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - New Kent County [oversize], 1876. (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Norfolk City, 1842-1851. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Norfolk County, 1800-1849. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Norfolk County, 1851-1860. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Norfolk County [oversize], 1853-1855, 1875, 1879. (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Northampton County, 1800-1849. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Northampton County, 1850-1860. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Northampton County [oversize], 1860, 1878. (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Northumberland County, 1800-1849. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Northumberland County, 1850-1859. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Northumberland County [oversize], 1876, 1879, 1909. (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Nottoway County [oversize], 1807-1829. (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Nottoway County, 1830-1851. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Orange County, 1800-1839. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Orange County, 1840-1851. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Page County, 1831-1853. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Page County [oversize], 1875. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Patrick County, 1800-1858. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Patrick County [oversize], 1875-1876, 1880. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Petersburg City, 1800-1854. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Pittsylvania County, 1800-1849, 1851, 1855-1856. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Pittsylvania County [oversize], 1850, 1852-1855, 1858-1859, 1861, 1863. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Portsmouth [oversize], 1876. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Powhatan County, 1800-1849. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Powhatan County, 1850-1864. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Powhatan County [oversize], 1874-1877. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Prince Edward County, 1800-1849. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Prince Edward County, 1850-1861, 1877. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Prince Edward County [oversize], 1863, 1875, 1877-1878. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Prince George County, 1800-1849. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Prince George County, 1850-1851, 1858-1859, 1875 bond. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Prince George County [oversize], 1857, 1860, 1863. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Prince George County [oversize], 1875, 1877-1881. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Prince William County, 1800-1849. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Prince William County, 1850-1860. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Prince William County [oversize], 1874, 1879. (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Princess Anne County, 1800-1849. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Princess Anne County, 1850-1860. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Princess Anne County [oversize], 1859-1860, 1877, 1879. (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Pulaski County, 1849-1852, 1859. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Pulaski County [oversize], 1875-1877, 1880, 1894. (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Rappahannock County, 1834-1845. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Rappahannock County, 1851-1863. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Rappahannock County [oversize], 1880. (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Richmond City, 1818-1849. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Richmond City, 1850-1854, 1857, 1859, 1860. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Richmond City [oversize], 1855-1856, 1858, 1894. (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Richmond County, 1800-1849. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Richmond County, 1850-1859. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Richmond County [oversize], 1864, 1875-1876, 1878, 1880, 1894. (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Roanoke County, 1851-1852. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Roanoke County [oversize], 1876, 1878, 1880. (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Rockbridge County, 1800-1849. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Rockbridge County, 1850-1860. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Rockbridge County [oversize], 1852-1854, 1858-1860, 1863-1864. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Rockbridge County [oversize], 1876-1881, 1894. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Rockingham County, 1800-1851. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Rockingham County [oversize], 1838, 1875-1878, 1881. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Russell County, 1815-1848. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Russell County, 1850-1860. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Russell County [oversize], 1864, 1875-1878. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Scott County, 1815-1849. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Scott County, 1850-1860, 1874. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Scott County [oversize], 1863-1864, 1876-1879, 1881. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Shenandoah County [oversize], 1800-1829, 1872, 1875-1881. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Shenandoah County, 1830-1856, 1871. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Smyth County, 1832-1845. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Smyth County [oversize], 1860, 1879. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Southampton County, 1825-1848. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Southampton County, 1850-1860. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Southampton County [oversize], 1852-1853, 1863-1864, 1872, 1874-1877. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Spotsylvania County, 1800-1849. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Spotsylvania County, 1850-1860. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Spotsylvania County [oversize], 1871, 1875-1878. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Stafford County, 1800-1860, 1874. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Staunton, 1840-1861. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Surry County, 1800-1849. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Surry County, 1850-1864. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Surry County [oversize], 1861, 1871-1872, 1876-1880, 1901. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Sussex County, 1800-1863. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Sussex County [oversize], 1871-1872, 1875-1881. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Tazewell County, 1800-1859. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Tazewell County [oversize], 1860. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Warren County, 1836-1849. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Warren County, 1850-1860. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Warren County [oversize], 1860, 1876-1877. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Warwick County, 1800-1849. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Warwick County, 1850-1860. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Washington County, 1812-1849. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Washington County, 1851-1858. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Washington County [oversize], 1876-1878, 1880. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Westmoreland County, 1800-1848. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Westmoreland County, 1850-1861. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Westmoreland County [oversize], 1860, 1875-1878, 1880. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Williamsburg City, 1821-1852. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Winchester City, 1844-1851. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Winchester City [oversize], 1859-1861. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Wise County [oversize], 1857, 1860, 1881, 1901. (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Wythe County, 1818-1856. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - York County, 1800-1852. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - York County [oversize], 1860, 1876-1877, 1880. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Reports, General, 1829-1830. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Ledger, Various Counties, 1846-1852. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Ledger, Various Counties, 1877-1885. (Box 28)
  - Ledger, Various Counties, 1884-1888. (Box 29)
  - Ledger, Various Counties, 1888-1889. (Box 30)
  - Ledger, Various Counties, 1890. (Box 31)
  - Ledger, Various Counties, 1891-1892. (Box 32)
  - Ledger, Various Counties, 1893. (Box 33)
  - Ledger, Various Counties, 1895-1896. (Box 34)
  - Ledger, Various Counties, 1897-1898. (Box 35)
  - Ledger, Various Counties, 1899-1907. (Box 36)
- Series II: West Virginia, 1800-1862., Extent: 7 boxes (3.45 cu. ft.). (Box 15-19; and 26-27)
  The West Virginia series, 1800-1862, is housed in seven archival boxes and is arranged alphabetically by city or county name. At the time the records were created the counties were part of Virginia, though since the state of West Virginia was created in 1861 the decision was made to maintain a separate series for West Virginia.
  - Barbour County, 1843-1851. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Berkeley County, 1800-1849. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Berkeley County, 1850-1860. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Boone County, 1847-1851. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Braxton County, 1846-1860. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Brooke County, 1808-1860. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Cabell County, 1814-1855. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Calhoun County [oversize], 1861. (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Clay County [oversize], 1860. (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Doddridge County, 1846-1859. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Doddridge County [oversize], 1859-1860. (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Fayette County, 1831-1852. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Fayette County [oversize], 1860. (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Gilmer County, 1845-1860. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Greenbrier County, 1800-1849. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Greenbrier County, 1851-1860. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Greenbrier County [oversize], 1861. (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Hampshire County, 1800-1834, 1851-1852. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Hampshire County [oversize], 1852-1857. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Hampshire County [oversize], 1858-1861. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Hancock County, 1848-1856. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Hancock County [oversize], 1860. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Hardy County, 1800-1848. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Hardy County, 1850-1855. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Hardy County [oversize], 1853-1856. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Hardy County [oversize], 1857-1861. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Harrison County, 1800-1851. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Harrison County [oversize], 1860. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Jackson County, 1832-1860. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Jackson County [oversize], 1861. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Jefferson County, 1800-1849. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Jefferson County, 1850-1860. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Kanawha County, 1821-1851. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Kanawha County [oversize], 1860. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Lewis County, 1817-1852. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Lewis County [oversize], 1860. (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Logan County, 1827-1851. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Logan County [oversize], 1860. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Marion County, 1851-1860. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Marshall County, 1840-1862. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Marshall County [oversize], 1861. (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Mason County, 1805-1853. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Mason County [oversize], 1853-1861. (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Mercer County, 1838-1851. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Mercer County [oversize], 1860-1861. (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Monongalia County, 1800-1849. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Monongalia County, 1850-1859. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Monongalia County [oversize], 1851. (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Monroe County, 1806-1859. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Monroe County [oversize], 1861-1864. (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Morgan County, 1829-1849. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Morgan County, 1850-1857. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Nicholas County, 1819-1851. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Ohio County, 1827-1846. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Ohio County, 1851-1862. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Pendleton County, 1821-1848. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Pendleton County, 1851-1855. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Pendleton County [oversize], 1856-1860. (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Pleasants County, 1860. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Pocahontas County, 1822-1860. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Preston County, 1824-1852. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Putnam County, 1851-1861. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Raleigh County, 1852. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Raleigh County [oversize], 1860. (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Randolph County, 1810-1849. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Randolph County, 1850-1860. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Ritchie County, 1843-1852. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Roane County [oversize], 1860-1861. (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Taylor County, 1845-1860. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Tucker County, 1859-1860. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Tyler County, 1815-1844. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Upshur County, 1851-1860. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Wayne County, 1842-1859. (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Wayne County [oversize], 1860. (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Wetzel County, 1846-1853. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Wheeling, 1853-1855. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Wirt County, 1848-1859. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Wirt County [oversize], 1860. (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Wood County, 1809-1860. (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Wood County [oversize], 1862. (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Wyoming County, 1851. (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Wyoming County [oversize], 1860. (Box 27, Folder 22)